Register of the Mozambican subject collection, 1938-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
Mozambican Subject Collection,
1938-2001
XX785
6 manuscript boxes, 1 phonotape cassette (2.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, reports, communiqués, press releases, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Mozambique, and to revolutionary movements, especially the Frente de Libertaçao de Moçambique, in Mozambique.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
FRELIMO.; Mozambique--History--Revolution, 1964-1975.; Mozambique--Politics and government--1975-; Mozambique.; Africa.; Phonotapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1938-1995. (Boxes 1-2)
  Clippings, communiques, pamphlets, press releases, printed matter and reports relating to political and social conditions in Mozambique
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1961-1994. (Boxes 2-3)
  Clippings, communiques, flyers, pamphlets, printed matter and speech relating to revolutionary movements in Mozambique
- MISCELLANEOUS FILE, 1994-1995. (Box 3)
  Button, calendar, election flyers, scarf, and shirt representing Frente de Libertacao, de Mozambique (FRELIMO)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, ca. 1988. (Cassette cabinet)
  One phonotape cassette
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after February 1995
- SUBJECT FILE, 1938-1995
  - General (Box 1)
  - Cabora Bassa Dam
  - Economics
  - Education
    - General
    - Associacao Academica de Mocambique
  - Foreign relations - United States
    - General
    - Congressional Research Service publications
    - Mozambique Information Office
    - Washington Office on Africa newsletters
  - Health. Acquired Immune Deficiency System (AIDS)
  - International support groups
    - Friends of Mozambique
    - Mozambique Support Network
  - Media
  - Political parties
    - Partido Democratico de Mocambique (PADEMO)
    - Partido Liberal e Democratico de Mocabique (PALMO)
    - Political Parties Act, 1991 January
    - Regulations for the formation and activities of political parties
  - Politics and government
    - General
    - Constitution, 1990 November
    - Opposition. Mozambique National Resistance (RENAMO)
    - Press conference (Box 2)
    - Press release
    - Speech, 1991 July
  - Religion
  - Women
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1961-1994
  - General (Box 2)
  - Comite Revolucionario de Mocambique (COREMO)
  - Frente de Libertacao de Mocambique (FRELIMO)
    - General
      - Clippings
      - Communiques
      - Press releases and statements
    - Congresses of the Central Committee
    - Constitution
    - Education
    - Foreign policy
    - International support groups
      - General
      - Africa Research Group
      - Angola Comite
      - Committee for a Free Mozambique
      - Irish Mozambique Solidarity
      - Liberation Support Movement (LSM)
      - World Council of Churches
    - Machel, President Samora. Includes speeches by Machel
    - Opposition
    - Women (Box 3)
      - General
      - Machel, Josina
      - Organizagco da Mulher Mogambicana (OMM)
  - Movimento Nacionalista Mogambicano (MONAMO)
  - Organizacao Da Mulher Mocambicana (O.M.M.)
  - Unico Democratica Nacional de Mogambique (UDENAMO)
  - Unico Nacional Africana de Rumbezia (UNAR)
- MISCELLANEOUS FILE, 1994-1995
  - Button (Box 3)
  - Calendar
  - Election flyers
  - Scarf
  - Shirt
- AUDIO-VISUAL, ca. 1988.
  - Phonotape cassette. "FRELIMO Freedom Songs: War on Want" (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
- Incremental Materials (Box 4-6:)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.